

Taisiia Kolienchenko MANUAL QA ENGINEER

CONTACT INFORMATION

Mobile: +38(066)269-97-32 **E-mail:** kolentk@gmail.com

Skype: faliflame

LinkedIn: Taisiia Kolienchenko

LANGUAGES

Ukrainian: native **Russian:** native

English: intermediate

CERTIFICATION

ISTQB Certified Tester, Foundation Level

Certificate No: 18-CTFL-140806-12 August 2018

SKILLS

Tracking tools:

Jira, Mantis, Trello

Methodologies:

Agile/SCRUM, Kanban

VCS:

Jenkins, TeamCity

RDBMS:

PostgreSQL, Oracle PL/SQL, MS SQL

TM Tools:

TestRail

Tools:

PuTTY, WinSCP, pgAdmin, Beta crashlytics, Testflight, App tester

PROFILE

With more than five years of experience in testing, I managed to work on a lot of different projects. I have practical knowledge and skills in manual testing. Also, I have successfully tested and implemented a project into the work process. Experience of managing a small QA team of six people.

EXPERIENCE

November 2016 – January 2020 Yukon Software LTD

Location: Chernivtsi, Ukraine

Position: QA Engineer, QA Team Lead

Since I started my career in Yukon, I have worked on at least six different projects. The main and the biggest one is a software platform that makes it possible to combine a lot of different systems and devices for working together and messaging between each other.

My responsibilities included:

- Reviewing requirements, their estimation;
- Test planning and execution;
- Performing functional, regression, usability, data migration testing;
- Web, mobile and cross-browser testing;
- Creating new and updating old test cases, checklists, test documentation;
- Reporting bugs and their retesting
- Close communication with developers and stakeholders;
- Mentoring trainees.

Skills: Jira, Mantis, Trello, Jenkins, PostgreSQL, TestRail, PuTTY, WinSCP, pgAdmin, Beta crashlytics, Testflight, App tester

April 2015 - July 2016

Logrocon Software Engineering

Location: Moscow, Russian Federation

Position: QC Engineer

I worked on two different projects such as a billing platform for mobile network operator and a website for buying tickets and online booking.

My responsibilities included:

- Performing functional, regression, usability testing;
- Web, mobile and cross-browser testing;
- Creating new and updating old test cases;
- Reporting bugs and their retesting.

Skills: Jira, TeamCity, Oracle PL/SQL, MS SQL

EDUCATION

National Research University of Electronic Technology (MIET)

Department: Department (Institute) of Economics, Management and Law Master's degree, Project Management, graduated with honors Location: Moscow, Russian Federation 2008 – 2010

Yuriy Fedkovych Chernivtsi National University

Department: Department of Economics Bachelor's degree, Industrial Management, graduated with honors Location: Chernivtsi, Ukraine 2004 – 2008 April 2011 - March 2015 **Greece Visa Application Center**

Location: Moscow, Russian Federation Position: Senior Specialist, QC tester

From May 2014 to March 2015 along with my direct responsibilities as a senior specialist, I also worked on the project - Remote Data Processing Unit as a QC tester.

My responsibilities related to testing included:

- Manual testing;
- Reporting bugs and their retesting;
- Creating stories for implementation of new features;
- Creating improvements for updating features that already existed;
- Integration a part of software into the work process (installation, user's manual preparation, training employees and control over the whole work process in the new system).

Skills: Jira

From April 2011 to April 2014 I worked as a senior specialist.

My main responsibilities included:

- Advising customers;
- Acceptance and processing of documents for visa, their hand-over to customers;
- Preparing daily reports;
- Teaching new employees;
- Work process coordination.